翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
In this lecture, we're going to build an array-based list.
在这堂课中，我们将构建一个基于数组的链表
But before we do that, I think it's important to ask ourselves, why?
但在那之前，应该问问自己为什么
Because you will remember, halfway through the previous lecture,
因为你们应该记得，上一节课讲到一半
we actually ended up with something really nice-- and nice linked list that we call a DList.
我们已经得到了非常不错的东西——称之为 DList 的链表
So a DList had some wonderful properties.
DList 有一些很棒的属性
If we wanted to add items, remove items, get items,
如果我们想要添加、删除、获取项目
all of them were fast.
所有操作都很快
And I also said that we avoided ugly special cases
我还说过我们避免了丑陋的特殊情况
by having the special topology where the empty list looks something like this.
通过使用特殊的拓扑结构，其中的空链表如下所示
And as you fill in items, you end up having a structure like this.
添加项目时，你最终会得到一个这样的结构
I'm not going to go back over it.
不再重复了
And you'll have a chance in project 1A to see just how this beautiful idea makes it not so hard to code up, at least, I mean, to me.
你将有机会在 project 1A 中看到这个美丽的想法是如何简化编码的
For you, you might have a little more struggle.
对你来说，可能会有更多的挣扎
That's OK.
没关系
But once you get the ideas down, you realize--
一旦你把想法写下来，就会意识到...
and I hope appreciate-- how good it is.
我希望你能欣赏到它有多棒
So all of these operations are fast.
所有操作都很快
The data structure is pretty beautiful.
数据结构非常漂亮
So the question is, why bother?
那么为什么要费心呢？
Why bother using arrays instead?
为什么非要使用数组呢？
And so let's talk about a limitation to lists.
让我们来讨论一下链表的限制
So in general, if you have a list, a lot of times, you want to be able to get a specific item out of it.
一般来说，如果你有一个链表， 很多时候希望能够从中得到一个特定项
So we might be able to ask a list something like,
我们也许可以请求这样的链表
could you get me item 2?
可以给我第2项吗？
So I'd say, get item 2-- get 2--
获取第2项
and it would return 17.
返回17
So it turns out, with this linked list implementation,
事实证明，这个链表的实现
it's going to be slow for long lists.
对于长长的链表来说很慢
And what I mean by slow is if you compare the performance of get operation to the performance of getLast, it'll take a lot longer.
我所说的慢是指
如果将 get 操作的性能与 getLast 的性能进行比较，需要的时间要长得多
So I'd like you to think about why that might be the case,
我希望你们想一想为什么会是这样
and for what inputs?
输入又是什么呢？
So ponder that for a moment, and I'll spoil it.
仔细考虑一下，一会揭晓
So the reason is that you have to actually scan to the desired position.
原因是你必须真的扫描到想要的位置
So if I want to get item 2, I have to follow the sentinel link, hop a couple of times, and get the 17.
如果我想要第2项，就必须沿着哨兵链接，跳几次然后拿到17
So while that's not so bad here, imagine you have a list that is a million items long and someone asked for item 500,000.
这里虽然不是很糟糕，但假设有个长达一百万项的链表，有人要求提供第五十万项
No matter what, you're going to have to end up scanning all the way through the list,
不管怎样，你最终都要扫描整个链表
and you'll reach the point in the middle, finally, and be able to return the item.
最后到达中间的点，然后返回
But it means you have to walk a really long list, which is going to be slow, compared to just getting, say, the last time.
但这意味着你必须遍历非常长的链表，与 getLast 相比太慢了
So how can we fix this?
怎么解决？
Well, I didn't actually make this slide blue and make you think about it.
我并没有把这张幻灯片做成蓝色，让你想一想
There are some ways you can maybe ponder it.
有一些方法你也许可以思考一下
But the two most obvious ways-- or the two most natural ways is
但最明显的两种方式，或者说最自然的两种方式
one, the thing we're going to do, which is to use an array instead, avoiding the need for any links,
1. 用一个数组来代替任何链接
because without a bunch of links, there is no need to reverse them.
因为没有一堆链接，就不必反转它们
And that'll make it fast.
这会让它变得更快
And there's another approach we'll discuss much later,
我们将在很久以后讨论另一种方法
where we can mess with the topology this list in a very clever way,
用一种非常聪明的方式处理这个链表的拓扑
and end up something-- with something that's a lot faster.
最终得到快得多的东西
But we won't discuss it today.
但今天不会讨论这个
So let's move on to the array list, then.
那么让我们继续讨论数组链表
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）